<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>NotNot Jake</title>
		<link>https://www.notnotjake.com/</link>
		<description>I'm Jake: I share my thoughts on Apple and life.</description>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>Copyright 2020, Jacob Gooch</copyright>
		<managingEditor>jake@notnotjake.com</managingEditor>
		<webMaster>jake@notnotjake.com</webMaster>
		<pubDate>03 Aug 2020 16:00:00 EST</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>03 Aug 2020 16:00:00 EST</lastBuildDate>
		<docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
		
		<item>
			<title>Thoughts on Apple Maps</title>
			<link>http://www.notnotjake.com/</link>
			<description>
			&lt;p&gt;The latest update to &lt;a href="https://overcast.fm/"&gt;Overcast&lt;/a&gt; includes a feature that I&amp;#8217;m especially proud of that took over a year to build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voice Boost 2&lt;/strong&gt; is an all-new audio engine that includes professional-grade, mastering-quality loudness normalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I &lt;a href="https://marco.org/2014/07/16/overcast"&gt;first introduced Overcast in 2014&lt;/a&gt;, Voice Boost was one of its headlining features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voice Boost&lt;/strong&gt; is a combination of dynamic compression and equalization that can make many shows more listenable and normalize volume across all shows. This makes amateur-produced podcasts (including many of my favorites) more listenable in loud environments, like cars, where you’d otherwise need to crank the volume so loudly to hear the quiet parts that you’d blow your ears out when the loudest person spoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voice Boost 2 achieves the same goal as the original Voice Boost, but with dramatically more sophisticated methods, leading to more consistent results and &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; better sound quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I wrote the original Voice Boost with only a rudimentary understanding of audio processing, it was a single configuration of Apple&amp;#8217;s AudioUnits that applied a fixed set of parameters to all podcasts, regardless of their audio characteristics. It was an effective but blunt tool, relying on aggressive &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dynamic_range_compression"&gt;level compression&lt;/a&gt; and a strong &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Equalization_%28audio%29"&gt;EQ&lt;/a&gt; to make the compression less noticeable.&lt;/p&gt;
			</description>
			<pubDate>03 Aug 2020 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.notnotjake.com/posts/</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>